Good evening, dear viewers. Good evening.
Today is August 9th,
Saturday, the 16th day of the intercalary sixth month in the lunar calendar,
Welcome to CCTV News.
First, let me outline today's program highlights.
This year marks the concept that "lucid waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets,"
which was first proposed twenty years ago.
Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China,
the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core has prioritized ecological conservation as a fundamental strategy for the sustainable development of the Chinese nation,
undertaking a series of pioneering initiatives,
Significant strides have been made in building a Beautiful China.
China Central Television News launches a special series,
documenting ecological transformations.
Today, we begin at the birthplace of the "Two Mountains" philosophy,
in Anji, Zhejiang Province.
All localities and departments have thoroughly implemented the important directives of General Secretary Xi Jinping,
carrying out all flood prevention and disaster relief tasks,
ensuring public safety. In our special series "Sixty Glorious Years,"
"The Enchanting New Tibet" airs today,
showcasing a better life through cultural and tourism integration.
For ethnic liberation and world peace,
the exhibition attracted over 300,000 visitors in July,
with the Consumer Price Index remaining flat year-on-year,
while showing a slight month-on-month increase.
Multiple countries and international organizations condemned Israel's plan to take over Gaza.
Russia stated that
the presidents of Russia and the United States will hold talks in Alaska on August 15,
focusing on long-term peaceful solutions to the Ukraine crisis.
Here's the detailed report.
In 2005,
In 2005, Comrade Xi Jinping, then Secretary of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee, first proposed during an inspection tour of a fishing village in Anji, Zhejiang,
the "Two Mountains" concept that "lucid waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets,"
profoundly illustrating the dialectical unity between ecological conservation and economic development.
Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China,
the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core has treated ecological civilization construction as a fundamental strategy for the sustainable development of the Chinese nation,
has undertaken a series of pioneering initiatives,
giving rise to Xi Jinping Thought on Ecological Civilization,
the advancement of ecological civilization across China
has undergone transformative changes both in theory and practice,
achieving historic and pivotal
comprehensive transformations
Significant strides have been made in building a Beautiful China.
Starting today,
China National Television will launch a special series
to witness ecological transformations,
through the strides of socioeconomic progress,
and from the daily lives of every citizen to perceive the green momentum of China's new era.
Today,
we begin at the birthplace of the "Two Mountains" philosophy,
starting from Anji, Zhejiang.
In the midsummer heat, the small town of Anji is lush with greenery,
bustling with crowds,
Over 22,000 sensors are scattered throughout every corner of the town.
The sensing equipment on the carbon flux monitoring towers in the bamboo forests,
continuously monitors every breath of the bamboo groves,
ultimately converting it into measurable data that quantifies the bamboo forest's carbon dioxide absorption and storage capacity.
Over the past decade,
the carbon sequestration per hectare here has increased to 6.6 tons,
making bamboo forests highly efficient carbon sinks.
The resulting carbon credits can be traded.
This generates over 28 million yuan annually in carbon storage revenue for bamboo farmers across the county,
A hyperspectral camera monitors this urban stream regularly, tracking changes in water pollutants like ammonia nitrogen.
Researchers transform the monitored data into visual maps like this,
where red indicates pollutants in the water.
Over a decade ago,
The entire stream was lined with red,
but now the red has vanished.
The overall local water quality has improved from Category IV to Category II, transforming into crystal-clear streams,
where over twenty rafting spots have emerged.
Summer tourism revenue alone now exceeds 200 million yuan.
What about the water back then,
it was pitch black,
the same color as the soy sauce in your home,
that's exactly how dark it was.
Now you can jump in anywhere,
You can even swim here,
Satellites have captured more changes from space.
Twenty years ago,
the mountains were dotted with over seventy mining sites and cement plants.
Today, the highly polluting chemical plants are gone—transformed into zero-carbon rural libraries and exhibition halls.
It now attracts over 1.2 million tourists annually.
This site, once Anji's largest limestone quarry, has been ecologically restored and
transformed into a scenic eco-resort with lush hills and water features,
selling over 8,000 cups of coffee daily at peak times,
matching nearly a year's revenue from its former mining operations.
Today in Anji, the stone-based economy has been replaced by a green economy,
with the county's GDP soaring from 8.896 billion yuan to 67.557 billion yuan.
proving that "clear waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets,"
This philosophy has spread nationwide from its origins in Anji,
evolving into a societal consensus and guiding principle for action.
Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China,
ecological civilization construction has been advancing comprehensively,
people have tackled pollution,
healed ecological scars,
and safeguarded nature with ecological conservation redlines,
integrating green transformation into production and daily life,
ecological conservation has achieved historic and transformative
changes on all fronts,
preserving our lucid waters and lush mountains,
across 9.6 million square kilometers of land,
The land now teems with vibrant green development.
Along the eastern foothills of Helan Mountain in Ningxia,
what was once a barren gravel wasteland has been restored,
transforming into China's largest contiguous wine grape growing region.
Lush greenery now stretches as far as the eye can see,
The economic returns are now substantially higher than before.
At the foot of Langshan Mountain in Shaoyang, Hunan, rice farmers have reserved foraging areas in their paddies for the cranes,
while strictly controlling pesticide and chemical fertilizer use,
successfully preserving the cranes' wetland habitat.
The rice produced here has become more sought-after in the market.
The rice fields cover 300 mu,
growing the Zhu Huan rice variety,
which sells for three yuan more per jin than regular rice.
Annually,
this brings in an additional 200,000 to 300,000 yuan.
In the tranquil forests of Sanming, Fujian,
life bursts forth in glorious bloom during summer.
Dendrobium officinale enters its maturation phase,
alongside golden-threaded lotus, multiflowered goldenseal, and crimson mushrooms,
transforming the entire forest into a treasure trove of sustenance.
These wild medicinal herbs and mountain vegetables growing in the forest,
generate an annual output value exceeding 100 million yuan.
In the past, we'd just chop some wood in these woods to earn a little money.
Now we're developing Ningxia's economy through
tourism initiatives,
During peak seasons,
we receive multiple groups of visitors daily.
If we protect the green mountains,
they will surely reward us in return.
Today, China has launched its first national pilot program for realizing the value of ecological products across twelve regions,
over 300 eco-tourism routes,
generating market vitality exceeding one trillion yuan.
The lush forests,
the fresh air,
and clean water sources are being transformed into tangible ecological commodities.
A sound ecological environment is the most inclusive form of public welfare.
The vivid practice of "lucid waters and lush mountains being invaluable assets"
is continuously writing new chapters.
At the instruction of General Secretary Xi Jinping,
Member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee
Vice Premier of the State Council Zhang Guoqing, representing the CPC Central Committee and the State Council,
Vice Premier Zhang Guoqing, representing the CPC Central Committee and the State Council, led relevant department officials to Yuzhong County in Lanzhou, Gansu Province on the evening of the 8th to direct on-site search and rescue operations and emergency response efforts for the mountain flood disaster.
Zhang Guoqing visited Maliantan Village in Mapo Township, the hardest-hit area,
Zhang Guoqing visited Maliantan Village in Mapo Township, Jiuzhuanggou Village, and the temporary shelter for relocated residents at Yuzhong County First People's Hospital,
conducting thorough investigations into search and rescue operations,
medical treatment for the injured,
the relocation and resettlement of affected residents, and other relief efforts.
Subsequently, he convened a meeting at the on-site command center,
to discuss and arrange support for Gansu's disaster relief and rescue operations.
He emphasized that,
General Secretary Xi Jinping has shown deep concern,
being deeply concerned about the safety of affected residents,
and has paid close attention to the progress of emergency rescue and relief efforts,
repeatedly stressing that
protecting people's lives must remain the top priority.
making every effort to search for and rescue missing individuals,
relocating and resettling,
residents in threatened areas,
and promptly restoring communication and transportation,
enhancing risk forecasting and early warnings,
strengthen the identification and rectification of potential hazards,
reinforce emergency duty shifts,
and issued clear directives to ensure public safety during the disaster season.
Premier Li Qiang issued instructions,
regarding rescue operations,
evacuation and relocation,
restoration of damaged facilities,
and enhanced disaster prevention and response measures.
Gansu Province and all relevant parties must resolutely implement the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the requirements of Premier Li Qiang,
and carry out targeted flood prevention and disaster relief efforts,
to minimize casualties and disaster losses.
Zhang Guoqing stressed that
With extreme weather events occurring frequently in recent times,
efforts must be made to improve the accuracy of rainfall forecasts regarding location, intensity, and timing,
and provide early warnings with sufficient lead time.
We must closely monitor areas prone to mountain torrent disasters,
geological hazard hotspots and other high-risk zones, as well as dangerous periods like nighttime heavy rainfall,
strictly implement early warning response mechanisms and emergency evacuation measures,
and ensure timely and thorough relocation when disasters strike.
All localities and departments have thoroughly implemented the important directives of General Secretary Xi Jinping,
continue to carry out all flood prevention and disaster relief work with full effort,
ensuring the public's safe passage through the flood season.
Since August 7th,
Lanzhou City in Gansu Province,
Yuzhong County and other areas have been hit by continuous heavy rainfall,
triggering mountain flood disasters,
affecting eight townships.
In Maliantan Village of Yuzhong County, the hardest-hit area,
rescue teams advanced on foot with equipment,
conducting overnight door-to-door search operations.
local stationed troops and militia,
the National Northwest Regional Emergency Rescue Center,
local rescue personnel and other forces jointly
continued advancing into severely affected Maliantan Village,
Jiuzhuanggou Village,
and Xinglongshan Village, with teams advancing along the river channels in separate groups,
intensifying search and rescue efforts for missing persons.
Currently,
on-site rescue operations are underway under urgent conditions.
We will resolutely implement the important directives of General Secretary Xi Jinping,
We will prioritize the search and rescue of missing individuals as our most urgent task at present.
As long as there remains the slightest hope,
we will never cease medical treatment for the injured,
while evacuation and relocation efforts for affected residents are also being intensified.
In Lanzhou,
At the First People's Hospital of Yuzhong County,
fifteen successfully rescued individuals are currently receiving treatment.
Most of them sustained soft tissue abrasions,
fractures, and other external injuries,
and are now in stable condition.
The Gansu Provincial Health Commission has deployed 26 medical specialists from various departments across six provincial-level hospitals to participate in rescue operations in Yuzhong County.
Currently, Yuzhong County has requisitioned hotels,
along with 54 temporary schools and village committees serving as 14 centralized relocation sites,
having relocated and accommodated a total of 9,800 affected residents.
Many evacuees were transferred here starting from around 8 pm last night,
Upon arrival, staff immediately arranged dinner for them,
which consisted of four stir-fried dishes.
This morning's meal was even more substantial,
with all aspects of support being exceptionally well-provided.
The heaviest rainfall was recorded at Xinglong Mountain in Yuzhong County.
Currently, emergency crews are racing to reopen Provincial Highway S104 - the main route connecting the county town to Xinglong Mountain.
Rescue teams are continuously reinforcing the roadbed along this section,
while clearing mudslides and debris.
As of 6 PM today,
80% of power supply has been restored in the affected areas,
Communication services have been largely restored.
The Office of the Committee for Disaster Prevention, Mitigation and Relief,
the Ministry of Emergency Management,
and the National Food and Strategic Reserves Administration
have allocated
including 10,000 relief items such as folding beds, cotton-padded quilts, and emergency lighting equipment.
These central disaster relief supplies
will assist local authorities in further strengthening emergency relocation/resettlement and disaster relief efforts for affected residents.
The Ministry of Finance
and the Ministry of Emergency Management have urgently allocated 120 million yuan in central natural disaster relief funds,
to support relief efforts in Gansu and Inner Mongolia,
with priority given to search/rescue operations and temporary relocation,
secondary disaster risk screening and emergency mitigation by affected residents,
and repair of damaged civil defense facilities.
Currently, we remain in the critical "late July to early August" flood season period.
To ensure public safety,
we're supervising localities to take proactive measures.
Today, Zhengzhou in Henan issued a yellow rainstorm alert,
where drainage pipelines have been cleared in advance,
catch basins dredged,
For flood-prone areas within the urban district,
relevant departments have also pre-deployed drainage pipelines,
and large mobile pumping vehicles.
Resolutely implementing the important directives of General Secretary Xi Jinping,
enhancing risk forecasting and early warnings,
strengthening the identification and rectification of potential hazards,
enhancing emergency duty shifts,
resolutely shouldering the political responsibility for flood prevention and disaster relief,
ensuring the safety of cities and the well-being of residents.
The National Meteorological Center forecasts that,
Over the next three days,
as the main rain belt shifts southward, heavy rainfall will affect regions from Sichuan
through Chongqing to Jiangsu
and Anhui.
The public should remain vigilant against severe convection weather and secondary disasters.
This station reports: To implement the important directives of General Secretary Xi Jinping, the Central Organization Department
has allocated 32 million yuan from the centrally managed Party funds to Gansu
and Guangxi provinces to support flood prevention and disaster relief efforts.
Tibet's natural landscapes,
along with its abundant and diverse cultural resources,
serves as a vital conservation area for distinctive Chinese ethnic culture,
and a premier global tourism destination.
In today's special report series "60 Years of Splendor: The New Charm of Tibet",
let us journey into the snowy plateau,
to explore how Tibet leverages its unique resources,
promoting the integrated development of culture and tourism,
to help local residents prosper.
Deep in the Nyenchen Tanglha Mountains,
at the foot of Mount Sapu in Nagqu, Tibet,
performers staged the Dabuxian dance.
This dance, which evolved from labor scenes,
is recognized as national intangible cultural heritage.
Watching this unique live performance at the foot of snow-capped mountains
offers visitors an immersive intangible heritage experience.
Building on these distinctive resources,
The local government is actively developing new cultural tourism consumption experiences.
Here, visitors from afar can gallop on horseback while sightseeing and capturing travel photos,
immersing themselves in unique natural landscapes and cultural charm.
In July this year,
the Sapu Scenic Area was officially certified as
a national AAAA-level tourist attraction,
receiving 16,600 visitors in the first half of the year,
marking a 150% increase compared to last year.
Although I've visited Tibet five times,
seeing it up close like this
Seeing Sapu still leaves me utterly awestruck.
This once-remote plateau wonder now welcomes more visitors with open arms,
while enabling locals to thrive through tourism right at their doorstep.
At 4,100 meters above sea level, the Tricolor Lake lies in Banbar County of Qamdo,
consisting of the White Lake,
the Yellow Lake, and the Black Lake.
The Tricolor Hot Springs are located in Puyu Village near the Tricolor Lake,
a village embraced by glaciers and lakes,
once the most isolated place in the surrounding area.
In recent years, with continuous improvements in infrastructure,
Particularly last September,
when National Highway 319 was fully opened to traffic,
the drive from here to Lhasa was shortened by nearly four hours.
The number of tourists visiting Three-Color Lake has surged exponentially,
bringing transformative changes to the villagers' lives.
My home is in Puyu Village,
the first guesthouse in the area,
My name is Dianji Diexina,
This is my father,
He's working on stone carvings,
That's my grandmother Puyu,
She comes here every afternoon for tea.
This is the most fun swing in our home.
Seven-year-old Dengzeng Dexi is the little star of the guesthouse,
His father Dorje is a painter,
Five years ago, he opened the village's first Tibetan-style guesthouse.
Today, the guesthouse earns an annual income of 100,000 yuan,
Last year alone,
Puyu Village's tourism revenue exceeded six million yuan,
With an average household increase of over 20,000 yuan.
This year's situation is even better,
with fifty or sixty,
earning six hundred yuan a day is quite substantial. By integrating local scenery with distinctive culture,
we're building Thangka villages,
woodcarving villages,
Tibetan-style villages, ethnic township villages and other distinctive rural communities,
and developing more premium tourism routes and products.
Since entering the new era,
Tibet has been thoroughly exploring and utilizing its cultural resources,
promoting the integrated development of culture and tourism,
The cultural tourism industry has shown vigorous development momentum.
Statistics show that,
in 2024, the region received over 63.89 million domestic and international tourists,
with total tourism expenditure exceeding 74.6 billion yuan.
representing year-on-year growth of 15.8% and 14.5% respectively.
For national liberation and world peace,
the thematic exhibition commemorating the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance Against Japanese Aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War,
has been open to the public.
Over the past month,
visitor numbers have surpassed 300,000.
The exhibition hall displays personal letters from General Zuo Quan among other artifacts.
Over 100 sets of Grade-1 cultural relics are on display, including Li Tianyou's notes from the Furong Military Academy.
Drawing visitors from all walks of life, the exhibition features a specially designated area honoring the spirit of the War of Resistance.
A memorial zone dedicated to fallen heroes of the war invites solemn reflection.
The names of renowned anti-Japanese martyrs and heroic groups are engraved on white walls flanking the space.
Visitors place their hands on the interactive display screen,
bow in solemn salute,
completing the flower-laying ceremony
to honor their memory.
In the audiovisual space featuring wartime family letters,
AI technology transforms these wartime letters
into condensed documentary films,
guiding audiences into the spiritual world of the martyrs who resisted the war.
Our fallen heroes advanced wave upon wave,
securing today's era of peace with their flesh and blood.
Only then can we pursue our dreams without worries.
We must channel our remembrance of the martyrs into concrete actions,
particularly by dedicating ourselves to our studies to truly serve our nation.
Data released today by the National Bureau of Statistics shows that
in July, the national Consumer Price Index (CPI) rose by 0.4% month-on-month, reversing the 0.1% decline from the previous month,
rising by 0.4% instead,
while remaining flat year-on-year.
The core CPI, which excludes food and energy prices, rose by 0.8% year-on-year,
marking the third consecutive month of expanding growth.
In July, service prices increased by 0.6% month-on-month,
accounting for over 60% of the total CPI increase.
Driven by peak summer travel season,
airfares, tourism,
hotel accommodations and related services saw significant month-on-month price increases,
while trade-in incentive policies for consumer goods showed notable effects,
new energy vehicles, automobiles,
Consumption of key commodities like home appliances continued to recover,
driving prices to stabilize and rebound,
Residents' cultural,
tourism, entertainment and other consumption potential kept being unleashed,
driving a broader increase in service prices,
Domestic market competition continued to improve,
leading to narrower price declines in coal,
steel, photovoltaic, and lithium battery industries.
In July, the Producer Price Index (PPI) fell by 0.2% year-on-year,
representing a 0.2 percentage point narrower decline compared to the previous month,
marking the first month-on-month narrowing of the decline since March.
Since the beginning of this year,
regions across China have leveraged their respective resource endowments and industrial foundations,
through industry-academia-research collaboration,
through policy support, funding assistance, and various other measures,
to accelerate the development of distinctive industrial clusters,
injecting strong momentum into high-quality economic growth.
In Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province,
this industrial cluster specializing in visual intelligence technologies,
has gathered over 10,000 industrial chain enterprises,
with upstream and downstream companies concentrated here,
cutting hardware iteration cycles by half.
In Bengbu, Anhui Province, this sensor industrial cluster
features various smart terminals capable of detecting
smart terminals that can detect environmental changes like temperature and light.
Its output value in the first half of the year increased by 36.5% year-on-year.
In the first half of this year,
regions across the country leveraged their local advantages
to accelerate the construction of industrial clusters with distinctive features.
Statistics show that
as of the end of June,
China had established 33 national-level manufacturing innovation centers,
cultivated a total of 80 national advanced manufacturing clusters,
300 national specialized SME clusters, and over 1,000 provincial-level specialized industrial clusters,
covering industrial clusters in next-generation information technology,
high-end equipment,
new materials, biopharmaceuticals and other fields,
This will better facilitate the integration of industries and production factors,
the convergence of innovation and industrial chains,
the integration of enterprises of all sizes,
further invigorating the economy,
and promoting coordinated regional development.
Next, China will focus on strategic emerging industries,
strengthening collaborative innovation across industry, academia, research, and application sectors,
guiding local governments to tailor policies based on the industrial characteristics and development needs of different clusters,
formulating targeted fiscal, financial, and talent support policies,
promoting the upgrading of specialized industrial clusters toward high-end,
intelligent,
and green development.
Next, let's take a look at a set of news briefs.
According to the latest statistics from the National Financial Regulatory Administration,
As of the end of June,
the balance of nationwide inclusive agriculture-related loans reached 13.94 trillion yuan,
representing an 8.34% increase since the beginning of the year.
The outstanding loans in key national grain sectors reached 5.1 trillion yuan,
marking a 13.5% increase since the beginning of the year.
From January to June this year,
the average interest rate for newly issued inclusive agriculture-related loans nationwide decreased by 0.61 percentage points year-on-year,
maintaining a downward trend.
According to reports from Chongqing Customs,
Since the implementation of the New Western Land-Sea Corridor master plan in August 2019,
the cumulative import and export volume through the corridor by provinces and regions along the route has exceeded four trillion yuan,
reaching 4.06 trillion yuan,
with three primary logistics modes established: rail,
sea-rail intermodal transport, international rail intermodal transport,
and cross-border rail transport—
connecting to 574 ports across 127 countries and regions.
Recently, the Tarim Oilfield photovoltaic power station—the largest in the heart of Xinjiang's Taklamakan Desert—
has achieved cumulative power generation exceeding 300 million kilowatt-hours.
The photovoltaic power station covers an area of over 3,300 mu (approximately 220 hectares),
consisting of nearly 260,000 solar panels,
and operates under an ecological model that generates electricity above the panels while stabilizing sand beneath them.
This represents a significant exploration of desertification control in hinterland engineering projects.
Two years have passed since the Shenzhen Park development plan for the Hetao Shenzhen-Hong Kong Science and Technology Innovation Cooperation Zone was released,
in international innovation,
talent mobility,
research funding,
cross-border utilization,
and streamlined customs clearance for research materials, among other areas, a series of innovative mechanisms have been explored.
To date, over 200 high-end research projects,
147 technology companies,
and more than 15,000 research professionals have been assembled.
The No. 8 Zoigê Tunnel on the newly constructed Xining-Chengdu Railway has been successfully completed.
The tunnel is located in Zoigê County, Sichuan's Ngawa Prefecture,
stretching 2,177 meters in length,
with an average elevation of 3,493 meters.
Its geological structure is complex,
making construction highly challenging.
The newly constructed Xining-Chengdu Railway,
has a main line spanning 836.5 kilometers,
with a designed speed of 200 kilometers per hour.
The entire line is expected to open to traffic in 2029.
As of noon today,
Since the beginning of this year,
The passenger volume on the Xiamen-Jinmen mini three links ferry route has exceeded one million,
representing a year-on-year increase of over 45%.
The one-way trip on the Xiamen-Jinmen mini three links ferry route takes less than half an hour,
with 24 round-trip sailings currently operating daily,
earning its reputation as a golden route for cross-strait travel.
The Ministry of Education
the "New Era Exemplary Youth" book campaign themed "Celebrating New China's March Toward a New Era" organized by the China National Working Committee on Children and Youth,
has been implemented in 220,000 primary and secondary schools nationwide since August last year,
Over the past year,
combining online and offline approaches,
Through youth reading programs and
patriotic literature reading activities,
guiding young people to love the Party,
their country, and socialism, the online campaign page has recorded over 14 million visits.
As of this afternoon,
By 2025,
the summer box office revenue has exceeded 8.2 billion yuan.
The war-themed film "Nanjing Photo Studio" has surpassed 2 billion yuan,
leading the box office charts.
With the release of multiple films including "Dongji Island,"
The summer box office continues its upward trend.
Since the beginning of this year,
China's film market has showcased diverse genres and
a wide variety of themes,
As of now,
The annual box office revenue has exceeded 35.5 billion yuan.
The Palestinian Health Ministry in Gaza reported on the 8th that in the past 24 hours,
Israeli military operations across multiple areas of the Gaza Strip
have resulted in the deaths of 72 civilians,
with 314 others injured.
The Israel Defense Forces announced on the 8th that they had destroyed rocket launchers belonging to Palestinian armed groups in the Gaza Strip,
weapons depots, and other facilities.
In response to Israel's announcement that
its military was preparing to take control of Gaza City in the northern Gaza Strip, Palestinian President Abbas's spokesperson Nabil Abu Rudeineh stated on the 8th that the Palestinian side is
making efforts at all levels to stop this act of Israeli aggression.
On the 8th, Hamas, the Palestinian Islamic Resistance Movement, condemned this as a right-wing war crime committed by Israel.
The United States bears responsibility for this.
On the 8th, UN Secretary-General António Guterres issued a statement,
expressing deep shock at Israel's plan to take control of Gaza City,
warning of a dangerous escalation in the situation.
Arab League Secretary-General Ahmed Aboul Gheit,
Jordan, Egypt,
Saudi Arabia, France,
the UK, Germany, and others condemned and opposed Israel's related plan on the 8th.
Germany announced on the 8th the suspension of military exports to Israel,
any military equipment that could potentially be used in the Gaza Strip.
The Russian Defense Ministry stated on the 8th that over the past week,
Russian forces launched attacks on Ukrainian command posts,
military airfields,
and unmanned boat production workshops, conducting seven concentrated strikes. Russian air defense systems
shot down a British-made Storm Shadow cruise missile and 1,508 fixed-wing drones.
The Ukrainian side simultaneously claimed that
Ukrainian forces repelled dozens of Russian attacks in the Toretsk and
Pokrovsk directions, among others.
Ukraine also stated that
[they] destroyed advanced Russian radar systems in combat.
Russian Presidential Aide Ushakov stated today that
Russian President Putin and U.S. President Trump will hold talks in Alaska, USA on August 15.
The focus will be on long-term peaceful solutions to the Ukraine crisis.
On the U.S. side,
On the 8th, the U.S. side stated that details of the presidential talks between the U.S. and Russia,
with the terms of the related peace agreement potentially involving territorial issues to be announced later.
Ukrainian President Zelenskyy said today that,
Ukraine is willing to accept a genuine peace solution,
but will not make concessions on territorial issues.
Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orbán stated earlier on the 8th regarding the Russia-US presidential talks that,
this is conducive to achieving peace.
He also reiterated that,
concerning the security issues of the European continent,
Europe should neither isolate itself from the matter nor blindly accuse Russia.
Europe should promptly convene a summit with Russia,
and resolve the conflict through dialogue.
Next up is a roundup of international news.
The World Trade Organization released its latest trade forecast report on the 8th,
projecting a 0.9% growth in global goods trade for 2025,
up from the -0.2% forecast in April.
The report also revised down its 2026 global goods trade growth forecast from April's projection of 2.5% to 1.8%.
The report noted that
Asian economies will remain the primary engine of global goods trade growth in 2025,
while North America will continue to drag on global trade growth over the next two years.
WTO Director-General Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala pointed out that
tariff uncertainties continue to weigh on business confidence,
investments, and supply chains,
making them one of the most disruptive forces in global trade.
Brazilian President Lula stated on the 8th that,
The Brazilian government will ensure that domestic exporters are not adversely affected by the U.S. tariff hike policy.
Brazil will not sacrifice the interests of its domestic agricultural
and fisheries export industries.
Lula emphasized at this juncture,
that the United States should learn to respect other countries' sovereignty and judicial rights.
The United States had previously announced the imposition of additional tariffs on Brazil,
while demanding that the Brazilian government halt judicial investigations into former President Bolsonaro.
Yemen's Houthi forces claimed on the 8th to have attacked Israel's Ben Gurion International Airport again, as well as the strategic targets of Ash,
Kiryat Gat, and Beersheba.
Since the new round of Israeli-Palestinian conflict erupted in October 2023,
The Houthi forces have persistently launched missile and drone attacks
targeting locations within Israel,
with the stated objective of supporting Palestinians in the Gaza Strip, while Republicans governing Texas in the U.S.
aim to solidify their party's majority in the U.S. Congress
by attempting to push through redistricting efforts.
On the 8th, California Governor Gavin Newsom, a Democrat, stated that
he would initiate a voter referendum in early November in the state,
also aimed at redistricting.
If the objective is achieved,
Democrats could gain five additional seats in the U.S. House of Representatives, according to those who attended Newsom's press conference that day.
U.S. media reported that some Texas Democratic legislators had previously left the state in an attempt to block redistricting efforts in Texas.
The battle over redistricting between the two parties is intensifying.
On the 8th, Spain's national meteorological agency stated that most regions of the country continued to experience high temperatures.
That same day, the central Spanish city of Toledo recorded the nation's highest temperature at 42.4 degrees Celsius.
Amid the scorching heat,
Wildfires continued to rage across multiple regions of Spain,
while a forest fire broke out in southern Athens, Greece on the 8th,
with strong winds causing flames to spread rapidly.
The fires have claimed at least one life so far.
The high winds also caused ferry delays and cancellations at ports near Athens.
Parts of France and Italy also continued to be affected by wildfires on the 8th.
That concludes today's news broadcast.
Thank you for watching.
For more news updates,
please follow the CCTV News app.
For more mobile videos, please download the Yangshipin app.
Goodbye!