Mm-hmm,
Good evening, dear viewers. Good evening.
Today is Sunday, August 10th,
the 17th day of the intercalary sixth month in the lunar calendar.
Welcome to CCTV News.
First, here are the main highlights of today's program.
Digital villages represent the strategic direction for rural revitalization.
President Xi Jinping emphasized that
we must seize the opportunities of digitalization,
networking,
intelligent transformation,
promote digital transformation in manufacturing,
service industries,
agriculture and other sectors,
Since the beginning of this year,
Regions across China have accelerated the development of digital rural infrastructure.
striving to enhance agricultural efficiency,
revitalize rural areas,
and increase farmers' incomes. This series of reports
captures the ecological transformation underway.
Today's broadcast
features our series "Keeping Blue Skies Permanent"
on the relentless implementation of the Central Eight-Point Regulation.
Today we visit Zhongwei in Ningxia, Dalian in Liaoning and other regions
that persistently advance rectifications
delivering tangible results,
ensuring the educational outcomes take root,
making them perceptible and accessible to the public.
The first comprehensive rehearsal for the commemoration of the 80th anniversary of China's victory in the War of Resistance Against Japanese Aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War concluded successfully.
In the first half of this year, China's light industry output above designated size grew by 7.0% year-on-year,
with revenue exceeding 11 trillion yuan.
Across all regions and departments, efforts are being intensified to advance flood prevention and disaster relief operations,
working at full capacity to safeguard people's lives and property.
Russian sources stated that,
Russian forces shot down a Ukrainian Su-27 fighter jet and 457 fixed-wing drones.
The Ukrainian side stated that,
Ukrainian drones struck a drone logistics hub inside Russian territory,
Here's the detailed coverage:
Detailed report follows.
Digital villages represent the strategic direction for rural revitalization.
President Xi Jinping emphasized that
we must seize the opportunities of digitalization,
networking,
and intelligentization,
to advance the digital transformation of manufacturing,
the service sector,
agriculture and other industries.
Since the beginning of this year,
regions across the country have accelerated the development of digital villages,
focusing on improving agricultural efficiency,
revitalizing rural areas,
increasing farmers' incomes—managing hundreds of acres of farmland with just a smartphone.
A single rural livestream
can help village agricultural products reach markets far and wide.
Digital technologies enter villages,
Many tasks can now be handled without leaving the village.
digital industries,
digital governance,
digital services for people's livelihoods,
Digital technologies are transforming the production and lifestyles in rural China.
President Xi Jinping has placed great emphasis on the development of digital villages.
He stressed the need to focus on the primary direction of agricultural modernization,
enhancing intelligent agricultural production and networked operations.
utilizing IoT (Internet of Things) and
other modern information technologies like big data to develop smart agriculture.
The General Secretary emphasized that
modern information technologies should be effectively leveraged to innovate rural governance methods,
thereby elevating the level of sound rural governance.
In implementing the General Secretary's directives, the Digital Village initiative has been consecutively included in the Central No. 1 Documents since 2018,
with successive releases of the Digital Village Construction Guidelines versions 1.0 and 2.0,
establishing the fundamental framework for China's digital village development.
Currently, broadband coverage has reached 100% of administrative villages nationwide,
with over 90% having 5G access, and the rural internet user population reaching 322 million.
Meanwhile,
the BeiDou Navigation Satellite System,
the construction of major data infrastructure including high-resolution Earth observation systems,
provides technological support for rural digitalization initiatives.
Well,
this year has seen further acceleration in rural digital development.
In March, eight key provinces including Zhejiang,
Anhui, Fujian,
Henan, Chongqing,
and Sichuan launched a special digital rural development initiative to strengthen agriculture, benefit farmers, and boost rural prosperity.
In May 2025,
the Digital Rural Development Guidelines were issued.
In the first half of this year,
China's e-commerce transaction volume for agricultural products grew by 17.2%.
Behind this growth,
lies the support of over 300,000 integrated village-level logistics service stations across the country,
The digital rural development initiative
has given rise to a thriving rural e-commerce industrial chain.
This is Xinhua Village in Cangxi County, Sichuan,
Now, with just an internet connection
and a smartphone, this small mountain village is connected to the world.
The village's specialty Cuiguan pears are reaching customers nationwide through livestream sales.
Meanwhile, across the entire Cangxi County,
virtually every village now has digital-savvy officials
who can film and host livestreams to promote local products,
along with a new generation of farmers specializing in product selection,
supply chain management, and after-sales services.
We will subsequently develop integrated models combining e-commerce with industrial e-commerce, rural tourism,
cultural and creative industries,
nurturing rural operation specialists,
agricultural innovators, and other new-generation farmers,
empowering our rural areas through digital means,
advancing digital governance in rural areas.
Now villagers can handle many municipal affairs without leaving their village.
In Yantao Village, Changxing County, Zhejiang,
villager Zhang Zhemin used the integrated government service machine,
and completed the modification of his medical insurance enrollment information in just five minutes.
Last year,
this procedure still required bringing documents to the county office for processing.
This year, Zhejiang is accelerating the implementation of its "one-network" digital rural governance system,
striving to achieve online application rates for provincial-level matters,
online processing rates,
online service completion rates,
zero in-person visits,
fulfillment rates,
and 100% electronic document usage—all five metrics,
ensuring rural and urban residents enjoy equal-quality services.
advancing urban-rural integration scenarios.
We will enhance the "one-network management" system,
enable one-click direct access,
and explore more AI-powered scenarios,
ensuring data not only flows swiftly,
but also flows accurately,
but also delivers tangible value,
enhancing the precision of rural governance while increasing villagers' sense of fulfillment
and well-being.
According to the plan,
By 2035,
significant progress will be made in digital rural development.
The urban-rural digital divide will be substantially narrowed,
farmers' digital literacy will be markedly improved,
driving comprehensive rural revitalization,
building a robust agricultural sector,
creating beautiful countryside,
and enabling prosperous farmers—air quality is closely linked to people's livelihoods.
President Xi Jinping emphasized that
we must restore clear skies and
a starry sky.
Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China,
China's air pollution control has accelerated remarkably, with increasingly more blue skies and white clouds,
bringing tangible happiness to the people.
Today's perceptible ecological changes,
Let's take a look at the changes brought about by this blue sky campaign.
Swinging on swings and feeding geese,
Who would have thought this was inside an operational steel plant in Xingtai?
Every weekend,
the influx of visitors,
has brought booming business to the small convenience store by the factory gate.
Drinks, ice pops,
and children's toys are selling like hotcakes.
In the past, nobody wanted to come here,
the air was choking.
The air pollution was once Xingtai's deepest affliction.
In 2013,
among the 74 key monitored cities nationwide,
Xingtai ranked dead last.
This is the Delong Steel Plant captured by environmental monitoring satellites at the time,
At the peak of the smog crisis,
the factory complex was barely discernible,
yet now it stands clearly visible.
Verdant greenery thrives.
The transformation in the steel industry epitomizes China's victorious battle for blue skies.
To restore blue skies for its people,
China has successively launched air pollution prevention campaigns,
including the three-year Blue Sky Protection Campaign and ongoing air quality improvement initiatives.
Since 2013,
the number of heavily polluted days has decreased by over 90%.
China has become the country with the fastest air quality improvement rate in the world,
blue skies are becoming more frequent,
and the scents in the air are also undergoing noticeable changes.
A Tsinghua University research team has reconstructed this olfactory evolution process using smell visualization technology.
A decade ago, we could frequently detect this coal-smoke odor,
This indicates extremely high concentrations of PM10 particulate matter,
along with odors resembling burnt matchsticks and disinfectant,
which are characteristic of sulfur dioxide,
and nitrogen dioxide levels were also notably elevated.
Over the past decade, concentrations of these pollutants have significantly declined,
Nowadays, not only are these unpleasant odors no longer detectable,
but during our experiments, we're also increasingly detecting compounds like pinene
and limonene.
These substances represent the fragrant scents emitted by plants and trees—a shift that reflects
China's increasingly precise strides in air pollution control.
In Beijing,
an integrated air-space-ground monitoring network
tracks over 3,000 roadways, 200,000 heavy-duty diesel vehicles, 2,000+ construction sites, and thousands of industrial facilities,
collecting hundreds of millions of data points daily,
enabling targeted pollution control measures.
Over these years,
Beijing's annual average PM2.5 concentration has decreased from nearly 90 micrograms per cubic meter to 30.5 micrograms.
But to achieve further improvement, we now need to focus on every 0.1 microgram reduction,
meticulously working to shave off each 0.1 microgram,
seizing every possible opportunity for improvement.
We analyzed air quality data published over ten years from 339 cities,
finding that PM2.5 levels per cubic meter of air had decreased by nearly 40%.
Consequently, the average number of blue-sky days per city increased by 22 days.
In today's China,
clear blue skies are no longer a luxury,
From rooftops in Tianjin, people can now see Beijing in the distance,
while in Chengdu's CBD, snow-capped mountains 200 kilometers away are visible right from residents' doorsteps.
The number of publicly designated stargazing spots nationwide has increased twentyfold since 2016.
Blue skies and white clouds are no longer rare sights these days—
encountering smoggy weather, however,
that would be something novel now.
Back then, we'd rush to take pictures whenever we saw blue skies,
but not anymore.
Now it takes a sunset glow,
or a rainbow,
we'd take photos.
Now that the air quality has improved,
our aesthetic standards have also risen.
In Ningxia's Zhongwei and Liaoning's Dalian,
during the in-depth study and implementation of the Central Eight-Point Guidelines,
adhering to open-door policy for soliciting opinions,
conducting thorough investigations and research,
advancing rectification efforts,
ensuring tangible results in implementation,
to solidify the outcomes of the education campaign,
making these benefits tangible and accessible to the public.
Since the launch of the education campaign,
Zhongwei City in Ningxia has mobilized Party members to engage with industrial parks and enterprises,
assisting them in resolving practical development challenges.
Concurrently, officials have been assigned to provide end-to-end support for major projects,
extending counter-based procedures to on-site services.
At this big data industrial park currently under construction in Zhongwei Industrial Park,
With the assistance of dedicated service personnel,
approval efficiency has been significantly accelerated,
achieving a one-third improvement over previous standards.
As for the entire process,
the government has also made substantial efforts,
providing one-on-one services to understand our company's issues,
and addressing problems with a pragmatic approach.
Currently,
Zhongwei City has conducted in-depth examinations of issues in rural revitalization,
people's livelihoods, and social governance improvement,
resolving over 1,600 public complaints and appeals.
The city has effectively translated educational achievements into practical solutions,
serving the public,
concrete actions to promote high-quality development.
Comrades have thoroughly studied and understood the important speeches and directives of General Secretary Xi Jinping,
guiding Party members and officials to better follow the Party's mass line in the new era,
using problem-solving to drive changes in work style,
and demonstrating firm support for the "Two Establishments" through concrete actions,
resolutely upholding the "Two Upholds".
During the educational campaign,
Dalian City in Liaoning Province focused on optimizing the business environment,
continuously advancing the initiative of having leading officials engage with projects
and enterprises through special campaigns,
to drive high-quality development.
This private aquatic product processing company struggled with recruitment during peak seasons,
and even assigned enterprise liaison officers couldn't retain top talent.
Through on-site visits,
they helped the company organize dedicated recruitment fairs both online and offline,
while also facilitating partnerships with universities,
encouraging college students to intern and seek employment there,
and establishing a fast-track channel for professional title evaluations.
These comprehensive measures have helped companies attract and retain talent,
providing us with substantial support,
allowing us to experience continuous improvements in the business environment,
and growing confidence in corporate operations.
Currently, Dalian municipal officials have conducted field visits and research at over 10,000 business entities,
establishing specialized service teams for credit finance,
commerce, logistics,
sci-tech talent,
taxation, and eight other specialized service teams,
addressing key and challenging issues through coordination meetings and scheduling sessions.
We have earnestly studied and implemented General Secretary Xi Jinping's important directives on strengthening the Party's conduct construction,
effectively translating educational achievements into tangible results in work implementation,
We have gained public trust through new achievements in improving work conduct.
According to the press center for the 80th anniversary commemorations of the Victory of the Chinese People's War of Resistance Against Japanese Aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War,
from the night of August 9 to the early hours of August 10,
the first comprehensive rehearsal for the 80th anniversary commemoration of the Victory of the Chinese People's War of Resistance Against Japanese Aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War was held in Beijing's Tiananmen area, with approximately 22,000 participants involved in the rehearsal and on-site support operations.
It was reported that the first comprehensive rehearsal included the commemorative ceremony,
including the ceremonial proceedings,
with primary focus on coordinating the commemorative assembly,
the internal coordination of all procedural elements,
and comprehensively evaluated the organizational support and operational command from all parties.
The orderly rehearsal successfully achieved its intended objectives.
Beijing authorities stated that
the drill operation has been successfully completed,
expressing sincere gratitude to the public for their understanding and support.
Data from the China National Light Industry Council shows
China's light industry maintained its upward recovery trend in the first half of the year, continuing the positive momentum since Q4 last year,
Production showed steady growth,
with the added value of light industry enterprises above designated size increasing by 7.0% year-on-year,
generating operating revenue of 11.3 trillion yuan.
In terms of the consumer market,
policy-driven effects were notably evident.
In the first half of the year, retail sales of eleven categories of light industrial goods exceeded 4.3 trillion yuan,
representing an 11.6% year-on-year increase.
This growth was driven by consumer goods,
trade-in policies,
electric bicycles,
household appliances, freezers,
washing machines,
gas stoves and other products achieved double-digit production growth.
As policies continued to intensify and expand in scope,
consumer potential was steadily unleashed,
household appliances and audiovisual equipment,
retail sales of furniture products grew by 30.7%
and 22.9% year-on-year respectively,
maintaining the robust growth momentum seen since the beginning of the year.
On the industrial upgrading front,
In the first half of the year, light industrial products accelerated their shift toward premium
and intelligent development,
with digitization among major light industrial enterprises
reaching an 86.2% adoption rate for R&D tools,
effectively driving large-scale production of high-value-added products.
Moreover, light industry exports have maintained their resilience.
In the first half of the year,
light industry exports reached $456.8 billion, with 11 out of 21 major sectors achieving year-on-year growth in export value.
Since the beginning of this year,
China has continued to advance trade facilitation measures,
has rolled out a series of practical measures,
effectively promoting both the stabilization and quality improvement of foreign trade.
The Fujian Pilot Free Trade Zone, leveraging the International Trade Single Window,
pioneered a smart service platform for RCEP tariff policies,
enabling instant approval and issuance of certificates of origin.
Fujian enterprises have independently issued origin declarations for export goods worth over 2.4 billion yuan this year,
ranking first nationally,
providing strong support for businesses expanding into RCEP markets.
In Qingdao, Shandong Province,
customs authorities are actively advancing a new supervision model of "single document, single container" for rail-sea intermodal transport,
Companies can complete customs clearance procedures for goods at inland ports,
including inspection and other formalities.
After being transported to the port via rail-sea intermodal trains,
the goods can be directly loaded onto ships without container transfers throughout the entire process,
eliminating redundant declarations with a single bill of lading for end-to-end customs clearance.
Since the beginning of this year,
Qingdao Port has handled over 1.74 million TEUs of rail-sea intermodal transport,
representing a 13% year-on-year increase,
maintaining its position as the top coastal port nationwide.
In Dalian, Liaoning Province,
In the Dalian Pilot Free Trade Zone, addressing the practical needs of lithium battery export enterprises,
authorities have innovatively introduced a reusable packaging inspection model for exported lithium batteries,
solving the high-cost problem of single-use traditional plastic packaging.
This year, the model has already facilitated the use of over 190,000 reusable packaging units,
helping companies save more than 38 million yuan in costs,
promoting the parallel development of eco-friendly packaging and energy conservation.
The national one-stop platform for inbound and outbound mail processing has officially launched.
Over the past month,
more than 90,000 cross-border mail items have been processed,
with an average clearance time reduction of five hours per item.
saving time
while also reducing the financial burden previously incurred from using agency services.
We have consistently prioritized facilitating cross-border trade as a key initiative,
continuously optimizing the declaration process,
streamlining and upgrading the smart port supervision system while maintaining strict safety standards,
enhancing customs clearance efficiency.
Moving forward,
Customs will continue to expand the coverage of reforms,
further invigorating foreign trade vitality,
facilitating better integration of Chinese goods into global supply chains.
In recent days, all localities and departments have resolutely implemented the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping,
carrying out targeted flood prevention and disaster relief efforts,
making every effort to ensure the safety of people's lives and property.
Today, search and rescue operations for missing persons intensified in Yuzhong County, Lanzhou City, Gansu Province.
Rescue teams were divided into groups to search along severely affected areas including Maliantan Village,
as well as Xiaokangying Village, areas downstream of Kanggu Reservoir, and along river channels.
while utilizing drones for aerial magnetic detection,
enabling more precise targeting of search areas as infrastructure repairs in affected zones continue to progress.
As of now,
all major power lines in the area have been fully restored,
The next step will shift to the power grid reconstruction phase.
Through measures such as erecting communication-supporting base stations and conducting repairs,
voice communication in severely affected villages has largely been restored to normal.
Today, the main road from Yuzhong County to Mapo Township—which was heavily impacted—
Provincial Highway S104,
the last flood-damaged section of the road,
allowing heavy machinery,
rescue vehicles, and supplies
to swiftly reach the disaster-stricken areas.
President Xi Jinping emphasized that,
Communications and transportation must be restored as soon as possible,
We immediately mobilized highway departments and related transport enterprises from five surrounding cities
and prefectures,
deploying a total of 130 pieces of machinery and equipment,
and dispatched 670 personnel.
Currently,
all disaster-damaged roads in Yuzhong County have been reopened to traffic.
After the disaster occurred,
the Ministry of Transport and the Ministry of Finance activated a rapid coordination mechanism,
allocating emergency road restoration subsidy funds,
to support emergency rescue and traffic maintenance efforts.
The Ministry of Water Resources instructed local authorities to conduct damage assessments and emergency repairs on rural water supply projects,
installing temporary water pipelines.
As of now,
Xiaguanying Town,
Three towns including Chengguan Town have fully restored normal water supply for 12,000 residents.
Since yesterday,
parts of Sichuan have experienced heavy to torrential rainfall,
with local authorities today upgrading to issue a heavy rain
yellow warning.
Chengdu railway authorities have suspended some trains bound for Beijing,
Shenzhen, Wenzhou and other destinations,
In some villages and towns of Mianzhu, twelve hours of rainfall
exceeded 200 millimeters at maximum,
prompting local authorities to evacuate and relocate over 200 residents overnight.
Multiple areas in Anhui experienced rainfall today,
with some parts of Jinzhai receiving over 150 millimeters of precipitation within six hours.
The rainfall exceeded 150 millimeters.
Local authorities cordoned off flooded sections of mountain roads,
deploying personnel for round-the-clock monitoring,
while conducting comprehensive inspections of geological hazard sites and
low-lying areas.
President Xi Jinping emphasized that
we must resolutely overcome complacency and negligence,
We will closely monitor weather changes,
mobilize village officials to intensify patrol inspections,
implement warning and precautionary measures at hazard sites,
while ensuring proper daily necessities for relocated residents.
Currently,
the National Flood Control Headquarters has activated a Level IV emergency response for Jiangsu,
Anhui, Hubei,
Chongqing, and Sichuan have initiated Level IV flood control emergency responses,
and dispatched task forces to Anhui
and Hubei frontline areas,
to assist in guiding flood prevention efforts.
Following the mountain torrent disaster in Yuzhong County, Lanzhou City, Gansu Province,
over thirty Party members from the Qilihe District Militia Emergency Company in Lanzhou formed a rapid-response team overnight.
They were the first to arrive at the worst-hit village,
evacuating residents and establishing supply channels for relief materials,
and threw themselves fully into emergency rescue operations.
At around 9:00 a.m. on the 8th,
the Party member突击队 (vanguard team) maneuvered for over an hour,
arriving at Mapo Township—one of the worst-hit areas—where all access roads to the disaster zone had been washed away.
The team members had no choice but to shoulder their shovels
and proceed on foot to Jiuzhuanggou Village,
clearing away mud, rocks, and fallen trees from the landslide while
simultaneously moving other large obstacles out of the way.
Every second counts in this rescue operation—
Every minute we save
means greater safety for the people.
In Jiuzhuanggou Village,
most houses in the First and Second Communities had been destroyed by flash floods.
leaving 175 villagers in grave danger,
the Party member突击队 of Lanzhou's Qilihe District Militia Emergency Company and arriving military troops worked together
to evacuate civilians when a river-crossing bridge was washed away,
The Party member突击队 urgently constructed a makeshift bridge,
ensuring the safe passage of residents.
At that time, a team of militiamen stood in the river water,
including the day when some of us carried the elderly and children,
and kept going,
The checkpoint at Liuli Point transferred me to the designated relief site,
Without them, our lives wouldn't be safe.
As night fell,
the Party member task force pressed on without rest,
carrying instant noodles,
bottled water,
folding beds, and other supplies,
shuttling between supply depots and centralized relief shelters.
At that moment, everyone had only one thought in mind:
no matter what difficulties they faced,
The disaster victims must be fed,
and not left to go hungry.
Currently,
the Party member突击队 of the militia emergency company remains on the front lines of rescue operations.
They have cleared nearly five kilometers of road silt,
transported nearly 2,000 relief items,
assisted stationed troops in evacuating and resettling nearly 400 affected residents,
salvaged and relocated nearly 100 pieces of disaster-affected supplies,
and transported over 20 tons of relief materials.
As the summer vacation passes its midpoint,
Cultural venues across the country are experiencing peak visitor numbers.
With exhibitions and activities continuously introducing fresh content,
museums and heritage parks have become not just summer classrooms where people gain knowledge
and experience history firsthand,
but also beloved cultural spaces and tourist destinations for visitors.
At the foot of Helan Mountain in Ningxia,
the Western Xia Mausoleum, which was inscribed on the World Heritage List this July,
has become a must-visit destination on northwest China's summer travel routes.
According to data from the Ningxia Culture and Tourism Department,
ticket reservations for the Western Xia Mausoleum scenic area have surged by 280% year-on-year.
Meanwhile, search popularity for nearby hotels and restaurants continues to rise sharply.
The visitor flow primarily comes from Beijing,
Shanghai, Hangzhou,
and parts of the Yangtze River Delta region in Jiangsu,
the Pearl River Delta, as well as some areas in South China.
During four consecutive summer seasons at the Liangzhu National Archaeological Park in Yuhang, Zhejiang,
the world's first large-scale VR experience based on the ancient Liangzhu city was launched.
Witness how our ancestors built water conservancy projects,
cultivated rice paddies,
and domesticated livestock.
The daily life of Liangzhu ancestors in this watery landscape feels almost within reach.
Here,
the ancient Liangzhu city has been fully digitized
and reconstructed,
allowing us to truly appreciate the remarkable ingenuity of their way of life,
including their jade artifacts,
their pottery works,
It's truly breathtaking.
Meanwhile, museums across China have launched new exhibitions this summer,
fostering increasingly diverse cultural exchanges,
breaking geographical barriers to reach wider audiences.
The Guangdong Museum has launched a new exhibition on the ritual and musical culture of the Xia, Shang, and Zhou dynasties,
featuring artifacts on loan from the Henan Museum,
the Wangziwu Ding, and other significant cultural relics.
Meanwhile, the China National Silk Museum in Hangzhou has gathered over 200 precious artifacts,
has launched the special exhibition "The Grassland Silk Road Across Vast Distances",
Each artifact embodies the distinctive dual styles of the Western Regions and Central Plains,
vividly showcasing the cultural convergence and collision along the 10th-12th century Grassland Silk Road.
The museum offers not only static displays,
but also dynamic educational journeys through grassland studies,
allowing historical culture to take root and flourish in children's hearts.
Within the ancient city of Weishan, Yunnan,
children roam freely,
immersed in the Nanzhao Museum,
experiencing the ambiance of ancient market life,
exploring ancient architectural structures.
wood carving techniques,
and even try their hand at crafting intangible cultural heritage items.
Since the summer vacation began,
Dali's Weishan County alone has received over 400,000 visitors,
visitor trips,
with study tour groups accounting for over 40% of the total,
The summer study tour market has shown rapid growth in overall volume.
Next up is a roundup of news briefs.
According to the Ministry of Veterans Affairs,
As of now,
China has established a comprehensive network of veterans service centers spanning from the national level,
provincial, municipal, county, township, and village levels
to communities, totaling over 610,000 six-tier veterans service stations.
Some localities have also set up veterans service stations in development zones, industrial parks,
large enterprises,
universities and other institutions,
A nationwide veterans service and support system with comprehensive coverage has essentially taken shape.
Recently, the National Development and Reform Commission and other departments issued guidelines on further leveraging the supervisory role of administrative reconsideration,
standardizing administrative law enforcement involving enterprises,
requiring strengthened governance over prominent issues regarding corporate fines,
with particular attention to maximum-amount penalties,
discretionary-basis-free penalties,
as well as conducting thorough reviews and corrections of excessive penalties for minor violations in cases such as cross-jurisdictional enforcement,
penalty-as-management practices,
prominent issues such as using fines as a means to increase revenue.
Construction of the nuclear island for Unit 1 of the Jinqimen Nuclear Power Plant in Ningbo, Zhejiang Province, commenced in full today.
The unit adopts third-generation Hualong One nuclear power technology. Once all six planned million-kilowatt nuclear power units are completed,
the annual power generation is expected to reach 55 billion kilowatt-hours.
Starting from August 15 this year,
Starting from August 15 this year, the registration process for Macau vehicles entering and exiting Hengqin has been simplified from the previous requirement of installing two electronic customs clearance tags (for both Macau and mainland China)
to only requiring the installation of a single Guangdong-Macao
jointly recognized mainland electronic tag,
allowing passage through the Hengqin Port to enter and exit the Guangdong-Macao In-Depth Cooperation Zone in Hengqin,
further enhancing customs clearance convenience.
The closing ceremony of the Smart Optics Valley CMG World Robot Skills Competition will air tonight at 8 PM on CCTV-1, featuring over 60 different types of robots.
gathered at China's Optics Valley,
showcasing more than 80 application scenarios.
Russia's Defense Ministry reported on the 9th that its forces shot down a Ukrainian Su-27 fighter jet and 457 fixed-wing drones,
and gained control of a settlement in the Donetsk region.
Russian forces also deployed Iskander missiles,
striking Ukrainian military targets in Chernihiv Oblast.
On the 9th, Ukraine's Security Service reported using drones
to attack a Russian attack drone and component logistics hub in the Republic of Tatarstan.
On the 9th, representatives from the UK, US, Ukraine, and several European countries held a meeting in the UK.
That evening, European officials issued a statement saying,
they would continue supporting Ukraine and maintaining restrictive measures against Russia.
The European side further stated,
any proposed solution to the Ukraine crisis
must safeguard Europe's security interests.
Chairman of the Russian Federation Council's International Affairs Committee Kara Sin stated,
the upcoming meeting between Russian and U.S. leaders
has left Europe feeling uneasy,
as Europe continues to cling to its irrational anti-Russia policies.
The Palestinian Health Ministry in Gaza reported on the 9th that the Israeli military's operations in Gaza over the past day
resulted in 39 Palestinian deaths,
with 491 others injured.
Additionally, the latest statistics from hospitals in the Gaza Strip indicate that
since early March this year,
the famine caused by Israel's ongoing blockade
has resulted in 217 deaths in the Gaza Strip.
On the 9th, the Gaza media office stated that the aid delivered to Gaza over the past two weeks
accounted for just over 10% of the actual needs.
On the 9th, Bahrain,
Indonesia, and 22 other Arab and Islamic nations, along with the Arab League and the Organization of Islamic Cooperation, issued a joint statement,
condemning Israel's plans to impose full military control over the Gaza Strip,
calling them dangerous and unacceptable violations of international law.
On the 9th, tens of thousands of
Israeli protesters took to the streets in Tel Aviv,
opposing the Israeli military's plans to take control of Gaza City,
demanding the Israeli government immediately cease military operations,
and secure the release of detained individuals.
Now for international updates:
London, the UK capital, saw protests and clashes on the 9th.
According to British media reports,
Protesters condemned Israel for committing war crimes in the Gaza Strip of Palestine,
while accusing the UK government of complicity. British police stated that
over 470 protesters were arrested that day.
According to U.S. media reports on the 9th,
multiple wildfires continue to spread across Southern California,
The Gifford Fire in Los Padres National Forest has now burned over 400 square kilometers,
making it the state's largest wildfire so far this year.
Another wildfire in Ventura County has spread into Los Angeles County,
destroying multiple homes in the area.
At least 2,700 residents have been forced to evacuate.
In eastern Canada,
Newfoundland and Labrador Province declared on the 9th,
that parts of the province have entered a state of emergency due to spreading wildfires,
with over 3,000 residents in the province under evacuation orders.
That concludes today's news broadcast.
Thank you for watching. For more news updates,
please follow the CCTV News app.
For more mobile videos, download the Yangshipin app.
Goodbye and see you next time, dear viewers.